A couple months ago, Andre Karpathy
released the idea of the LLM wiki. It's
a pattern for building personal
knowledge bases using LLMs and it
totally took off and for good reason.
There's a lot of power in the simplicity
here. So, this single markdown document
in GitHub called it gist got to 40,000
stars. And seriously, you can take this
file, copy it, paste it into your coding
agent, and ask it to build you an LLM
wiki and it's going to be able to just
basically oneshot it. So, it's really
easy to get started. And the idea here
is when we're building a personal
knowledge base for our second brain,
instead of just dumping in a bunch of
documents or indexing things for rag, we
can have the LLM help us build something
smarter, incrementally building and
maintaining a persistent wiki with
structured interlink collections of
markdown files. And so the idea here is
as we're adding in more sources over
time like meeting transcripts, plan
documents, articles from online, it's
going to not just index it, but it's
going to read each file, extract key
information, and integrate it into the
existing wiki. So updating things like
the entity pages that it creates over
time, so we have that knowledge graph
for agent to traverse through and
remember all the important information
that we're bringing in. So, at this
point, pretty much everybody is building
their own LLM wiki in their second
brain. But this isn't enough. And the
main problem that we have here is when
you take this gist and you build your
own version of an LLM wiki, it's going
to be structured differently than the
next person doing the same thing.
There's no standard. And so, there's
really not a way to share your LLM wiki
with someone else. And that's a bummer.
You can think of a lot of different use
cases where you'd want to curate a
knowledge base over time and then share
it with other people like other people
on your team. Maybe you want one wiki
for the team that everyone's second
brains are accessing independently.
Maybe I want to create a wiki for my
YouTube content and then share that with
you. There are a million reasons. But if
your agent doesn't know exactly how I've
structured my wiki with the different
metadata and my entity files, it's not
going to be able to search through it
optimally. We need a standard so that
everyone's building wikis in the same
way so that we can share them freely.
And so that is what Google has released
here with their open knowledge format.
It is a beautifully simple thing just
like Harpathy's LLM wiki idea where it's
just a simple standard built on top so
that you can guarantee you're building
your wiki in a way where other people's
second brains can understand it and vice
versa. And so in this video I want to
cover why OKF is so powerful. It really
is the future of personal agents. And I
want to show you how easy it is to get
started with this standard, both for new
LM wikis and even transferring existing
ones into this format. Very easy to do
that. And no matter the wiki, no matter
how much you're going to share it or
not, this is important even as an
optimization on top of Karpathy's LM
wiki idea. And I know that Google is
lagging in the AI race right now. Gemini
is not as good as GPT and Claude, but
they have been releasing some really
good stuff on how to leverage LLMs
effectively. And I think that's a
totally different lane than building
LLMs. Well, so I think this is something
really worth leaning into even if OKF
doesn't end up becoming the standard
down the line for personal agents.
There's going to be something like this.
And so it's good to understand this now.
Okay. Now, let's really get into OKF. So
there are two things that they're
standardizing here. The first is how we
are organizing information like our
entity documents and our concepts. And
then the second standardization is the
exact fields that we're going to have in
our metadata. So this is the information
that we tag at the top of every single
document to give the agent a richer set
of information. So we can even like
query based on the title or the tags. So
we have categorization. This is one of
the most important things to let the
agent traverse through our wiki like a
knowledge graph. And really the best way
to make this concrete for you is to show
you what a traditional Karpathy wiki
looks like. So we'll take a look at
this. This is one of the first wiks that
I built when Karpathy released this
idea. And then we'll get into some of
the problems that we have here. So at
the top of every single wiki is your
index file. You have the agent maintain
this every single time it's bringing new
information in. And the index file, it
reads this when it's first searching
through your knowledge base, pretty much
every single time. And so this just
gives you a high-level overview of all
the documents that you have access to in
the wiki. So the article and then a
quick summary so it knows if this is
something that it should look into based
on the user's request. And so every
single time we add in new documents,
this is evolving. And so the agent will
read this and then based on what we
asked it to do or the question, if it
figures like I should look at superbase
o this concept right here, this entity
document, then it'll drill into this. We
also have the metadata like I talked
about earlier like the title and the
tags so that it can also search based on
this like if it wants to look at the
category of security then it can filter
out just those documents and so then we
have the full sort of like skill.md here
this is like progressive disclosure like
skills where the index tells it the
knowledge it has and then it can read
the full document if it's appropriate
and then we also link to related
concepts down here and that link is what
really gives us this graph view where
You can see how all of our entities and
other documents are connected together.
So, the agent can sift through this to
really get a comprehensive set of
information if the question really calls
for it. And so, looking at one of these
documents here, it might feel like it's
overwhelming to build up all this
knowledge over time, but seriously, with
an LLM wiki, you are just giving the
reins completely over to an LLM. So, you
don't have to be technical. You don't
have to spend a lot of time maintaining
this. Literally the whole benefit of the
wiki is that up until we've had LLMs for
this, it was way too tedious to create
this sort of knowledge base where we're
responsible for understanding related
concepts and building that over time as
we're adding in new information. Like
there's so much tedious work here that
LLM are really, really good at. But as
much as they're good at this, they
aren't going to create this system in
the same way that someone else will with
with their LLM, right? like the way that
we link related concepts might be
different. The way we structure
information, even the metadata, like
what if we don't have tags, but we have
a field called categories. I mean, even
something as simple as that, that that
little change might make it so that if I
gave the knowledge base to another
person's agent, it wouldn't know how to
search through things categorically. It
would have to dive into the metadata
first to understand that, and it might
not decide to do so. I mean, all these
little problems will start to compound
when you don't have the same metadata,
you don't have the same folders. That's
what we're looking to do here with OKF.
All right. So now, if you want to build
with OKF, create a new knowledge base
with this format or even refactor one to
use the open knowledge format, look no
further than their spec.md file. So,
this is in their repo. I'll link to it
in the description. This is just like
Karpathy's gist where you copy this
document. Like you literally just click
this one button right here, put it into
your coding agent, and tell it to either
build you a wiki following the open
knowledge format or even refactor an
existing one. Like I said, it's going to
knock either of those out of the park
because this is kind of like a skill. It
teaches the coding agent everything it
needs to know about the standard. Like
here is the terminology. Here's how we
structure the bundles. I'll show you
more on this in a little bit. Here is
how we build the YAML front matter.
different attributes that we have for
each one of our documents like the tags
for categorization, right? Like this
single source of truth is all that it
needs. And because it's such a simple
format, a simple standard overall, it's
not really going to get confused going
through this. I mean, it's a pretty long
file, but in terms of what large
language models can handle these days,
especially with, you know, GPT 5.5 or
Opus 4.8, this is not much instruction.
And it it also doesn't really matter the
scale of your current knowledge base if
you are refactoring because you can
specifically ask it to use sub agents to
work through the different sections of
your knowledge base to refactor it to
this format. So really easy to scale,
really easy to just have the agent rip
through this spec. The sponsor of
today's video is Post Hog, a single
place for you to understand how users
are actually using your application to
debug and fix issues and test and roll
out all of your changes. And I'm excited
for this because I am using Post Hog
myself in Archon, my open-source AI
coding harness builder. I'm legitimately
leaning on the data insights that I get
from Post Hog every single day so that I
know exactly how to improve Archon in
the way that users actually need. And
installing Posthog is incredibly easy.
You just click on the install with AI
button on their homepage that I'll have
linked to in the description and boom,
it's a single command you can run a
wizard that will essentially be a senior
engineer helping you set up analytics
for your entire application in just
minutes. And you can also create custom
data views like this is the dashboard
that I'm looking at every single day to
see how people are actually using
Archon. And then we can also drill down
to get very granular as well. So the
individual runs of Archon, I can click
into this here to see all the details.
And so we can go very high level all the
way to individual parameters as we need.
It's got the analytics for everything.
And so production is the time where you
can't be flying blind. When you have
something deployed out to the world, you
need observability. And Post Hog is the
best for that. So I'll have a link in
the description. I would highly
recommend checking them out. And I
talked about this a little bit at the
start of the video, but this really is
the future of personal agents. It's like
what MCP did for agentto tool
communication, this OKF is doing for
agent to knowledgebased communication.
And one of the most important things in
the spec here is that they talk about it
being a standard both for consuming
knowledge bases like searching through
them, but also producing knowledge
bases. How do we evolve the wiki over
time? build up the entity pages like
Karpathy talked about in the initial
gist. We really are building on top of
it. And one of the really interesting
things to think about here is yes, this
is fantastic for sharing knowledge bases
or having a teamwide knowledge base.
This is also really good though even if
you're never going to share a knowledge
base. Think about this. If everybody has
the same standard for how they are
building up their own personal knowledge
base, everyone can share ideas more
like, oh, here are the entity pages that
are working really well for me and this
is how I want to organize things under
the standard. And then because you have
the standard as the foundation, it's
easier for other people to take those
ideas. And so what we're also I think
what we're going to see is like yes, I
don't think OKF is going to in the end
be the standard, but we're going to see
something like that and we're going to
see the standard evolve over time so
that it's easier and easier for people
to create these really rich knowledge
bases without having to spend a lot of
time upfront designing it with the LLM.
Now, of course, sharing wikis with other
people is the biggest benefit of OKF.
And that leads me into the example that
I have for you that's also a gift I'm
very excited to share. I have built a
bundle, that's what you call an OKF
Wiki, that packages up all of my
favorite AI coding YouTube videos on my
channel. And so, here's the thing. I'm
excited for this. I know that a lot of
you, you don't watch my entire video
every single time. You're going to sift
through things. You're going to just
take the transcript and feed it into
your second brain and ask questions. You
guys are already doing something like
this, but now making it easier for you
because I'm prepackaging up sets of
videos. I actually want to start doing
this so that you can very easily bring
it into your second brain and ask
questions as it relates to what you
actually care about or what you are
working on specifically. And so take a
look at this. All you have to do is
first of all take this spec and give it
to your coding agent. You have it teach
itself OKF. And then you go to this repo
with my AI coding knowledge bundle. I'll
have this linked in the description as
well. And you just paste this prompt
into your coding agent. That's it. You
give it the link to this repo. You tell
it to read the readme and set up
everything and it already understands
OKF. So, it links those two things
together. Brings the bundle into your
local Obsidian or Notion or whatever
you're managing your knowledge. And then
boom, you can instantly start asking
questions. You don't have to bring in
the transcripts yourself. This is the
easiest way for just content creators in
general to share their knowledge with
the world. They can create bundles. I'm
creating bundles for all my videos now.
And so this is just one example of what
OKF unlocks for us. And so I'll also
show you what this bundle looks like
because it's a really good example of
what OKF is really doing for us. All
right, let's get into the belly of the
beast. Now I'll show you how I've been
setting up OKF and we'll get into the
example bundle as well. And so something
that I do for my second brain, every
single system that I build in, I always
have a tople document that talks about
how it works. Like this is how I'm
working with OKF bundles. And then here
are the different bundles that I have.
So I basically have an index so it knows
the different bundles that it can go
into and search and read the index that
we have in there. So we kind of have
like two layers of indexing. And then I
also built a simple CLI script. This is
actually there in the example bundle
that you can clone that makes it easy
for it to in the command line list out
my bundles to view a specific index and
then you know once it finds one of those
files it wants to read then we have the
command line tool to read by a specific
bundle and concept ID. So I've added
like a little bit of organization on top
of OKF with just how I manage many
different bundles but otherwise I'm
following the format exactly. And so
let's actually look at one of these.
I'll click into bundles here and we'll
go into the one that I just shared the
GitHub for. So, if we look at the index
here, we can see that I have two
different sections and this is actually
a smaller bundle. So, I didn't want to
do something super complicated. So,
there really are just two sections. I
have the videos that I've put in this
bundle, which it's it's rather small.
There's only four videos, but these are
like the best and most up-to-date ones
on my channel for AI coding. And then I
have the concepts as well. So different
things that I talk about throughout
multiple of the videos that I want to
extract into its own entity page. And so
the index here says here are the
sections. And then I don't actually have
a list of each one of the individual
files because I'm just going to have the
agent read the files that we have in
concepts or videos, right? Like it can
list out here are all the files or it
can read the index within concepts
itself, right? So, however you want it
to navigate, it's going to be able to go
through these different layers of
documents or just do a keyword search.
And so, clicking into any one of these,
like the PIV loop, for example, this is
the primary mental model that I always
teach for AI coding. Very important to
have a process for yourself to plan,
implement, and validate whatever you're
creating with a coding agent. And so, we
have the YAML front matter at the top.
And the type, this is what is required
by OKF. It is the single required field
in the metadata because this is what
gives categorization to your documents.
So like this is the type of concept. If
I go to a video here, the type is video.
So we can search over just the videos
over just the concepts which is
especially powerful once you get bundles
that are a lot bigger than this. Again,
this is just an example here. But then
we also have all of the optional titles
in OKF. So title, tags, related videos.
This is how we link things together,
right? Like you saw with that other wiki
I showed earlier, it was just things
were linked at the bottom. However, this
now makes it so it's easier to navigate,
creating a standard for how we are
linking our entities together. And so
each one of these are optional. Only
type is required in OKF. But just
because you don't always have these
doesn't mean that your agent won't
understand it, right? Like if your agent
is a consumer of OKF, if you gave it the
spec and taught it to be a consumer,
it's going to know how to leverage these
fields for better searching and
traversing through the knowledge graph
that we have here. And so then this is
just all of our information on the piv
loop. I kept it nice and simple. And
then also linking to videos as well,
which maybe is like a little bit
redundant with related videos. So I
could probably make this bundle a bit
better, but I just wanted to have this
as an initial example. And it is
something that you can immediately bring
into your second brain. Just start
asking questions. Like I'll show you an
example here in my terminal. So first of
all, at the top level of my second
brain, I just asked what bundles do I
have? It ran a command here. So it used
that little CLI tool to list out all the
bundles that I have. And then it told me
that and then I just asked it a
question. So not even telling it what
bundle specifically to look through. I
said, "What's Cole's single biggest idea
for getting reliable code out of an AI
coding assistant?" and it ran four
commands in total. So first of all it
decided to read the coal AI coding index
that's the GitHub that I have for you
and then based on the index it knew like
okay let's take a look at the concepts
here and then from the concepts it's
like okay the single most important
thing I don't know what in the index
told it that but it's like context
engineering let's read the concept of
context engineering so we can see the
progressive disclosure as the agent is
figuring out where it needs to look down
to find the answer for me and then we
get the final answer here So just
beautiful to watch it work. When we have
something structured like this, it's so
easy for it to start with really not
much context at all and then drill down
into exactly what we need. That's what
OKF gives us as a standard. All right.
So if you're not sold on the idea of
having a standard for the LM wiki at
this point, I don't know what to tell
you. The one critique that I think is
actually pretty valid with OKF is a lot
of people are saying that it's too
simple, right? like there's not a lot of
value or substance that's actually added
on top of the Karpathy wiki. So, I've
I've seen that a few times just as I've
been doing a lot of research. I mean, I
put a lot of time into prepping for
these videos. I think it's kind of valid
because if we look at like what it's
really doing on top of the Carpathy
wiki, it's it's speaking to like exactly
how you organize your different files.
Like they they specifically have like
indexes within the folders and a top
level index like you saw in my bundle. I
mean, that's something I didn't really
have in wikis before. And then we have
the specific fields in our metadata like
the type is required. The other ones are
optional but these are the ones that
they recommend. Like that's pretty much
it. It's how we organize and what is the
metadata. That's pretty much all that we
actually have in the standard. And so
like the argument is kind of valid where
it's like what is it really giving? Like
there's there's not much there. But I
think that's also the point, right? Like
minimally opinionated. It's the bare
minimum layer that we need on top so
that we can produce and consume these
wiks in exactly the same way across
everyone's agents that lean into OKF.
Like I think that's actually a good
thing. I think that's a benefit, not a
downside. The fact that there's not much
substance here might seem
counterintuitive, but I think that is
actually a good thing. And I encourage
you just try out the bundle that I have
for you here. give it the spec and then
give it this prompt and then just start
asking questions about AI coding like
how I use sub aents uh what is the piv
loop like just start asking and and
seeing how easy it is for your agent to
grab those things for you and so that's
everything that I got for you today on
OKF really is the future of personal
agents if you appreciated this video
you're looking forward to more things on
AI coding and second brains I'd really
appreciate a like and a subscribe and
with that I will see you in the next
video.